# Anil Maharjan



maharjananil1@gmail.com



+977 9849205589



linkedin.com/in/anil-maharjan-313a00132

# **Summary**

Marital Status: Married

Gender: Male

**Professional Summary** 

Experienced Java developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Python (Programming Language), Microsoft Word, Jerseys, PHP, and Hibernate. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelors in Information Management focused in Information Technology from National college of computer studies.

# **Experience**



# Java Software Engineer

Aricalot Technology

Oct 2021 - Present (11 months +)

Pacesetter

- US base application for calculating and maintaining taxation process
- Develop APIs, integrate third-party payment gateway (Stripe, Authorize), integrate Accounting application

(Quickbook)

Technology used: Jersey, PostgreSQL

# **Java Software Engineer**

Batas Technology

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year)

Application to match service provider and service seeker

- · Develop APIs and services
- Technology used: Jersey, MySQL

• Application to provide farmers facility to sell their products to best bidding buyers. The application aims

remove middlemen and increase profits for farmers.

Develop APIs and services



# 🍄 Java Software Engineer

**Treeleaf Technologies** 

Jan 2019 - May 2020 (1 year 5 months)

Savx

- Blockchain base wallet for money transfer, forex, payments
- Developed APIs and Microservices
- Technology used: JxRs (Jersey), GO Lang, Protobuff, GRPC, MySQL, Redis **RCCS**

- Application to fetch data from RCCS cancer patients' data.
- Devel oped APIs to fetch data
- Technology used: Jersey, Protobuff, MySQL

### Simple School

- Application to monitor students' meals for schools.
- · Design database, developed APIs and services
- Technology used: Jersey, Protobuff, MySQL

### **JELP**

- Application for requesting help from nearby people in emergency
- · Design database, developed APIs and services
- · Technology used: Jersey, Protobuff, MySQL

### **Treeleaf Website**

- Design changes, Content changes
- Technology used: Html, CSS

### **Brilltech Website**

- · Design changes, Content changes
- Technology used: Html, CSS

### Suchi

- · Application to maintain inventory and credit system for small vendors
- Database design, develop APIs and services
- Technology used: Play, MySQL, Protobuff

### Anydone

- Application for matching service providers and service seekers using AI
- Database design, development APIs, and services
- · Technology used: Play, MySQL, Protobuff

# Java Software Engineer

# **HARATI Software**

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018 (3 months)

Was involved in the development of branch-less banking application

- Was assigned role to develop API
- Technology used: Spring boot, MySQL

# 🔼 Java Software Engineer

### **ITGlance**

Aug 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 2 months)

Was involved in designing a Database and setting up projects for the restaurant management system.

 Was involved in US based project called "On Target", an application that helped in project management,

visualizing project progress, map 3D module of engineering projects.

- Was assigned the task to develop APIs, integrate APIs to import data from the similar applications (Procore)
- Technology used: Spring boot, PostgreSQL

### 🔼 Intern

### **ITGlance**

Jun 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 3 months)

- Learning and Implementing Spring Boot project
- Involve in a project "Pharmalink", which aims to maintain medicine levels in different medical shops
- Was assigned as a team leader of the intern group which consists of two backend developers including me and

two frontend developer.

- Was involved in integrating API with Angular.
- Technology used: Spring boot, MySQL

# **Education**

National College of Computer Studies

Bachelors, Information Management 2013 - 2017

National College of Computer Studies

Intermidate 2011 - 2013

Whitefield Higher Secondary School

School Leaving Certificate 1997 - 2011

# **Skills**

api • artificial intelligence • Java • Spring Framework • Play Framework • gRPC • Jenkins • Docker Swarm • MySQL • PostgreSQL